PETER BAGGETTA B.ENG

(416)854-5405 \(\phi \) peter.baggetta@gmail.com \(\phi \) github.com/PeterBaggetta \(\phi \) https://peterbaggetta.com/

PROFILE

As a recent Computer Engineering graduate with up-to-date knowledge and strong problem-solving abilities, I am a dedicated and dependable worker. My diverse experience in office settings and development has honed my clear communication skills and enables me to collaborate effectively in various work environments as I pursue my P.Eng. license.

SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

- 4 years Git, GitHub & GitLab
- 4 years HTML & CSS, C & C++
- 4 years MATLAB & Simulink & R
- 3 years Python, Java & JavaScript
- 3 years Verilog, VHDL & assembly
- 3 years NodeJS, React & React Native
- 2 years PHP, SQL & NoSQL, Spring Boot, React, Junit, Jira, Figma & Cloudflare
- 1 year Microsoft Azure, Maven, Docker, Bitbucket, Cloudinary & SwiftUI

- AWS Solutions Architect Knowledge Badge (AWS Cloud Technologies)
- Quartus, Vivado, Cadence, & Xilinx
- Windows, Mac & Linux experience
- FreeRTOS, I2C, SPI, ARM Cortex
- TCP/IP & SNMP protocols
- FPGAs and SoC Device (ARM & x86) programming in VHDL, Verilog, MIPS/ARM assembly & C
- Keil & IAR Compiler workflow

PROJECTS

AES Encryption Coprocessor in CBC Mode

• Implemented an AES co-processor on a DE1-SoC development board. The project was developed using Verilog and C code within the Quartus Prime II FPGA Software IDE.

Data Compression in an Edge Computing Environment using an Auto-Encoder

• Created a Python and C-based data compression auto-encoder to evaluate CPU performance and power usage in an edge computing environment, optimizing both compile and runtime processes with various compilers.

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineering Intern, Publicis Sapient

Toronto, Ontario

- JUNE 2022 AUGUST 2022
- Developed a website using Spring Boot, React, and NodeJS to host and manage advertisement campaigns, enabling efficient creation, editing, viewing to be distribution to customers.
- Utilized Bitbucket, REST, CI/CD Pipelines, Docker, Kubernetes, Microsoft Azure and MongoDB for development and deployment.
- Contributed to \$1 billion in media sales, collaborating with skilled developers and maintaining partner relationships through Agile-based weekly meetings.

MAY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Supply Chain Intern, Bernstein Diet & Health Clinics

Toronto, Ontario

- Tracked medical orders using in-house software, making timely deliveries, and providing usability suggestions.
- Supported IT by collaborating on hardware upgrades, system migrations, and validating new software, while also handling high-order volumes during peak seasons.

Landscaping/Maintenance Team, Copper Creek

Kleinburg, Ontario

- MAY 2020 SEPTEMBER 2023
- Worked in a senior role within the landscaping team.
- Trained new employees to utilize different equipment and informed fellow coworkers on WHMIS safety measures.

Lifeguard & Swim Instructor, University of Guelph

Gueipii, Giitario

SEPTEMBER 2019 – FEBRUARY 2023

- Ensured the safety of 200+ guests in and around swimming pools, remaining vigilant at all times.
- Provided tailored swimming tips to boost confidence in individuals with limited swimming abilities and resolved conflicts as a leader among lifeguard colleagues.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Computer Engineering, University of Guelph

Guelph, Ontario

- SEPTEMBER 2019 APRIL 2023
- Graduated with High Honours
- Dean's List, 4 consecutive semesters